Virginia Gildersleeve International Fund Records, 1969-2012
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. COMMITTEES
  - PART III.
    - Project grants
      - 2000
        - #1361 Peru: Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
        - #1364 Ecuador: Fundacion de la Mujer (Box 62, Folder 3-7)
        - #1366 Cameroon: Ntarbang Women's Group (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - #1370 Sierra Leone: Krim Community Development Project Women's Program (Box 62, Folder 9)
        - #1379 Nigeria: Association of University Women, Ikeja Branch (Box 62, Folder 10)
        - #1383 Ghana: Lotus Children's Centre (Box 62, Folder 11)
        - #1385 Switzerland: IFUW Special Project Base Camp (Box 62, Folder 12-17)
        - #1387 Bangladesh: Integrated Development Organization (Box 62, Folder 18)
      - 2001
        - #1408 Bangladesh: Tribals (Box 62, Folder 19)
        - #1409 Liberia: Salayea District (Box 62, Folder 20-21)
        - #1444 Ghana: Womens Association of Science and Mathematics Graduates (Box 62, Folder 22)
        - #1448 Cameroon: Gender Mainstreaming and Networking Association (GEMANO) (Box 62, Folder 23-25)
        - #1457 Kyrgyzstan: New Perspectives Fund (Box 62, Folder 26)
        - #1472 Turkish Association of University Women (Box 63, Folder 1)
        - #1486 Cameroon: Association of University Women (Box 63, Folder 2)
        - #1482 Kenya: Nyikwasara Women Development Group (Box 63, Folder 3)
        - #1487 Kenya: Sourcenet (Box 63, Folder 4-5)
        - #1492 El Salvador: Asociacion de Mujeres Universitarias (Box 63, Folder 6-8)
        - #1495 Zimbabwe: Association of University Women (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - 2002
        - #1511 Tanzania Support and Training of Youths and Widows (Box 63, Folder 10)
        - #1512 Ghana: Muslim Women Action Against Traditional Practices (Box 63, Folder 11)
        - #1543 Croatia: Association of University Women (Box 63, Folder 12)
        - #1548 Uganda: Kaabong Women's Group (Box 63, Folder 13)
        - #1563 Haiti: Fonkoze (Box 63, Folder 14)
        - #1567 Ghana: Kopega Rural Community Women Development Group (Box 63, Folder 15)
        - #1571 Fiji: Association of Women Graduates (Box 63, Folder 16)
        - #1574 Bangladesh: Community Development Welfare Foundation (Box 63, Folder 17)
        - #1578 Nigeria: Aku Women Self-Help Group (Box 63, Folder 18)
        - #1600 Niger: Micro-Credit in Africa, Inc. (Box 63, Folder 19)
        - #1601 Russia: Federation of University Women (Box 63, Folder 20)
        - #1607 Kenya: Kabuor Young Sisters Theatre Group (Box 63, Folder 21)
        - #1613 Vanuatu: Association of Women Graduates (Box 64, Folder 1-2)
        - #1631 Australia: Federation of University Women (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - 2003
        - #1639 Ukraine: Social Nonprofit Organization Women of Crimea (Box 64, Folder 4-5)
        - #1653 Bangladesh: Rural Unfortunates Safety Talisman Illumination Cottage (RUSTIC) (Box 64, Folder 6-7)
        - #1654 Bangladesh: Sammilani Sheba Sangstha (Box 64, Folder 8-11)
        - #1659 Kenya: St. Jude Jumuiya Self Help Group (Box 64, Folder 12)
        - #1661 Cameroon: Abache Ejagham Mmbo Oblo (Box 64, Folder 13-15)
        - #1667 Uganda: Efforts of Women Association (Box 64, Folder 16-19)
        - #1668 Ghana: Diagnostic Women's Movement for Science Development (Box 64, Folder 20-21)
        - #1681 Bangladesh: Uttaron Samaj Kallyan Samity (Box 64, Folder 22-23)
        - #1683 Kenya: Centre for Kager Women (Box 65, Folder 1)
        - #1690 Cameroon: Association for Female Physics Teachers (Box 65, Folder 2-3)
        - #1692 Afghanistan Women Council (Box 65, Folder 4-8)
        - 1701 Chile: Cooperation Internationale pour le Equilibres (C.I.E.L.O.) (Box 65, Folder 9-11)
        - 1702 Ghana: Adawukwao Women Trader's Association (Box 65, Folder 12)
        - 1708 Philippines: Pine Tree (Box 65, Folder 13)
        - #1714 Tibet: The Shenpen Fund (Box 65, Folder 14-15)
          [see also: #2192 in box 71, folders 1-3 and Audiovisual materials]
        - 1727 Kenya: University Women Bursary Fund (Box 65, Folder 16)
        - 1733 India: Integrated Women Development Institute (Box 65, Folder 17-20)
      - 2004
        - 1748 Kenya: Gitaru Marigu Development Group (Box 65, Folder 21)
        - 1776 Kenya: Mwamba Self Help Group (Box 65, Folder 22)
        - 1782 Nigeria: Centre for Healthworks, Development, and Research (CHEDRES) (Box 66, Folder 1-6)
        - 1834 Guatemala: Friendship Bridge, Inc. (Box 66, Folder 7-9)
        - 1850 Ghana: Gbefi Community Women and Girl Child Empowerment Training Center (Box 66, Folder 10-12)
        - 1861 India: Women and Children Development Charitable Trust (Box 66, Folder 13-16)
        - 1866 Georgia: Association of Kvemo Kartli (Box 66, Folder 17)
        - 1876 Switzerland: International Federation of University Women (IFUW) (Box 66, Folder 18-19)
        - 1885 Cameroon: Working Group on Girls (Box 66, Folder 20)
        - 1892 Uganda Gender Rights Foundation (Box 66, Folder 21)
        - 1892 Uganda Gender Rights Foundation (Box 67, Folder 1-6)
        - 1893 Ghana: Deprived and Destitute Youth Restoration Centre (Box 67, Folder 7)
        - 1894 Papua New Guinea: Rhode Island Zoological Society (Box 67, Folder 8-12)
        - 1895 Albania: Rruga Me Pisha Foundation (Box 67, Folder 13-15)
        - 1910 Bangladesh: Esho Banchte Shikhee (EBAS) (Box 67, Folder 16-17)
        - 1921 Ghana: Women's Wing of Sanctified Truth (Box 67, Folder 18-20)
        - 1921 Ghana: Women's Wing of Sanctified Truth (Box 68, Folder 1)
        - 1941 Tanzania: Juhudi Women Group (Box 68, Folder 2)
        - 1944 Sierra Leone: Agency for Rural Development (AFRA-SL) (Box 68, Folder 3-5)
        - 1948 Benin: Women Education and Resource (Box 68, Folder 6-7)
        - 1953 Burkina Faso University Women Association (Box 68, Folder 8-9)
        - 1955 Nepal: Women Support Cooperative (WSC) (Box 68, Folder 10-11)
        - 1966 Ghana: Women Action for Change (WAC) (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - 2005
        - 1980 Nigeria: Action for Women and Children Organization (AWCO) (Box 68, Folder 13-14)
        - 1983 Ghana: Muslim Women Action Against Traditional Practices (Box 68, Folder 15)
        - 1992 India: People's Association for Rural Development (PARD) (Box 68, Folder 16-20)
        - 1995 Kenya: Wahanda Women Development Group (Box 68, Folder 21-22)
        - 2013 Suriname: Stichting Kraktie (Box 68, Folder 23-24)
        - 2013 Suriname: Stichting Kraktie (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
        - 2022 Tajikistan Branch of International Association "Women of Orient" (Box 69, Folder 3-4)
        - 2035 Sierra Leone Association of University Women (Box 69, Folder 5)
        - 2040 Bangladesh: Platform of Women's Empowerment and Rights (POWER) (Box 69, Folder 6-7)
        - 2055 Rwanda: Doctors on Call for Service, Bethsaida Center (Box 69, Folder 8-10)
        - 2056 India: S.P.Y. Reddy Youth Association (Box 69, Folder 11-12)
        - 2070 Kenya: Kager Self Help Group (Box 69, Folder 13-15)
        - 2075 India: Economical Housing and Agricultural Development Society (Box 69, Folder 16-20)
        - 2081 Philippines Association of University Women (Box 69, Folder 21-25)
        - 2083 Haiti: Friends of the Children of Laschobas (Box 69, Folder 26)
        - 2092 Fiji Association of Women Graduates (Box 70, Folder 1)
        - 2094 India: Rural Development Women Welfare Society (Box 70, Folder 2-7)
        - #2105 Nigeria: Farmers Development Association (Box 70, Folder 8)
        - #2130 Tanzania: Nyasura Women Group (Box 70, Folder 9)
        - #2153 Georgia: Studio Mobile Accent on Action (Box 70, Folder 10)
        - #2161 Uzbekistan: Women's Center Mansura (Box 70, Folder 11-13)
        - #2168 Thailand: The Professor Khun Duangduen Bisalputra Foundation (Box 70, Folder 14-15)
        - #2175 The Burundi Association of University Women (Box 70, Folder 16-17)
        - #2183 Bangladesh: Thikana (Box 70, Folder 18)
        - #2189 Nigeria: Community of Women Living with HIV/AIDS (Box 70, Folder 19-20)
        - #2192 Tibet: Shenpen Fund (Box 71, Folder 1-3)
          [see also: #1714, box 65, folder 14-15 and Audiovisual materials]
        - #2195 Bolivia: Polytechnic Institute Tomas Katari (Box 71, Folder 4-10)
        - #2200 Egypt: Association for the Development and Enhancement of Women (ADEW) (Box 71, Folder 11-13)
      - 2006
        - #2236 Sierra Leone: Teblahun Community Agricultural Development Association (Box 71, Folder 14-15)
        - #2237 Kenya: Huruma Women's Group (Box 71, Folder 16)
        - #2261 Haiti: St. Boniface Haiti Foundation (Box 71, Folder 17-18)
        - #2275 Argentina: Fundacion Leer (Box 72, Folder 1-5)
        - #2304 Georgia: Association of Kvemo Kartli "The Woman and the World" (Box 72, Folder 6)
        - #2332 Tanzania: Women Promotion Centre (Box 72, Folder 7-8)
        - #2350 Nepal: Women Support Co-operative Ltd. (Box 72, Folder 9-10)
        - #2369 Palestine/West Bank: Ibdaa Cultural Center's Ibdaa Health Committee (Box 72, Folder 11-12)
        - #2371 Paraguay: Project for the People of Paraguay (Box 72, Folder 13)
        - #2398 Dominica Grand Bay Village Council (Box 72, Folder 14)
        - #2408 Samoa: Apolima-uta Primary School Committee (Box 72, Folder 15)
        - #2417 Kenya: Bogiakumu Village Women (Box 72, Folder 16)
        - #2417 Kenya: Bogiakumu Village Women (Box 73, Folder 1)
        - #2469 Cameroon: African Action on AIDS Inc.
          - General (Box 73, Folder 2)
          - "Fighting Hunger with Cassava" Recipe book (Box 73, Folder 3)
        - #2487 Nigeria: Silverline Development Institute (Box 73, Folder 4-7)
        - #2491 India: Social Education and Environmental Development Scheme (SEEDS) (Box 73, Folder 8-10)
        - #2510 Turkish Association of University Women (Box 73, Folder 11)
        - #2514 Tanzania: Women Rights Action Group (Box 73, Folder 12)
        - #2539 Senegal: Women's Global Education Project (Box 73, Folder 13)
        - #2556 Uganda: Sacred Heart Sisters of Kitintale (Box 73, Folder 14-15)
        - #2595 Samoa: Gagamalae Primary School (Box 73, Folder 16)
        - #2606 Chile: Latin American Office of French NGO CIELO (Box 73, Folder 17)
        - #2636 Bangladesh: Ankur (Box 73, Folder 18-19)
      - 2007
        - #2691 Uganda: Women Prisoners Support Organization (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
        - #2714 Kenya: Girl Child Counseling Group (Box 74, Folder 3-4)
        - #2726 Indonesia: Institute for Women's Human Rights (Box 74, Folder 5-7)
        - #2727 Tanzania: Environment and Development Foundation (Box 74, Folder 8)
        - #2744 Nepal Association of University Women (Box 74, Folder 9)
        - #2761 Georgia: Women's Center (Box 74, Folder 10-16)
        - #2784 Liberia: The African Network for the Prevention and Protection Against Child Abuse and Neglect (ANPPCAN) (Box 74, Folder 17-19)
        - #2787 Hope Foundation for Women and Children of Bangladesh (Box 75, Folder 1)
        - #2803 Pakistan: Seeking of Light, Identity and Development (SOLID) (Box 75, Folder 2-3)
        - #2816 Cameroon: Apiculture and Nature Conversation Organization (ANCO) (Box 75, Folder 4)
        - #2854 Tanzania: Equality Now Advocacy (Box 75, Folder 5)
        - #2861 Ghana: International Federation of Lawyers (Box 75, Folder 6-7)
        - #2887 Trinidad and Tobago: Fyzabad Composite School (Box 75, Folder 8-9)
        - #2896 Switzerland: International Federation of University Women (Box 75, Folder 10)
        - #2909 China: Yunnan Institute of Development (Box 75, Folder 11-13)
        - #2922 Sierra Leone: Life for Relief and Development Orphanage (Box 75, Folder 14)
        - #2932 India: Rural Development Women Welfare Society (Box 75, Folder 15-16)
        - #2937 Kenya: Maasai Community Outdoor Educator (Box 76, Folder 1)
        - #2944 Guatemala: Asociation Tejadoras Unidas (Box 76, Folder 2)
        - #2948 India: Bharathi Educational Society (Box 76, Folder 3)
        - #2949 Burundi: Association for the Promotion of the Well Being (Box 76, Folder 4-5)
        - #2997 Rwanda Association of University Women (Box 76, Folder 6)
        - #3083 Azerbaijan: Sheki Branch Development of Women Center (Box 76, Folder 7-8)
        - #3088 Colombia: LIMPAL (Box 76, Folder 9-11)
      - 2008
        - #3122 Uganda: Miroi Growers Cooperative Society (Box 76, Folder 12)
        - #3124 Malawi: Tutulane AIDS Organization (Box 76, Folder 13)
        - #3137 Rwanda: Charity Group Association (Box 76, Folder 14-15)
        - #3167 Liberia: Volunteers to Support International Efforts in Developing Africa (Box 76, Folder 16-17)
        - #3179 Pakistan: Social Transformation and Educational Prosperity (Box 76, Folder 18)
        - #3180 Kenya Association for Empowerment of Disabled People (Box 76, Folder 19)
        - #3187 Kenya: Bogiakuma Village Women Group (Box 77, Folder 1)
        - #3225 Nigeria: Silverline Development Initiatives (Box 77, Folder 2-6)
          [see also: flat file]
        - #3228 Uganda: Cranes School: Semuto (Box 77, Folder 7)
        - #3237 Sierra Leone: Child Rescue and Welfare Organization (Box 77, Folder 8)
        - #3246 India: Rural People's Welfare Organization (Box 77, Folder 9-11)
        - #3261 Cameroon: Bongeh Women Common Initiative Group (Box 77, Folder 12)
        - #3276 Cameroon: Ntankah Village Women Common Initiative Group (Box 77, Folder 13-14)
        - #3281 Sierra Leone: Craftshare Vocational Training Centre (Box 77, Folder 15)
        - #3300 Tanzania: Amani Group for Development (Box 77, Folder 16)
        - #3390 Sudan: Ofirha Community Development Association (Box 77, Folder 17-18)
        - #3440 Burundian Women for Development Association (Box 77, Folder 19)
        - #3471 Nigeria: International Federation of Women lawyers (Box 77, Folder 20)
        - #3471 Nigeria: International Federation of Women lawyers (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - #3520 India: Good Hopes Educational Committee (Box 78, Folder 2)
        - #3522 Uganda Association of University Women (Box 78, Folder 3-4)
        - #3601 Nicaragua: Centro Cultural Batahola Norte (Box 78, Folder 5)
        - #3627: Uganda: The International HUG Foundation (Box 78, Folder 6)
        - #3628 Ghana: Divine Favour Agency (Box 78, Folder 7)
        - #3638 Azerbaijan: Digital Development (Box 78, Folder 8)
        - #3658 Ghana: Association for Women Empowerment (Box 78, Folder 9-10)
        - #3660 Serbia: Anti-Drugs Association (Box 78, Folder 11)
        - #3669 Peru: Union de Femeninas (Box 78, Folder 12)
        - #3671 Zimbabwe: Family-In-Need Trust (Box 78, Folder 13)
        - #3720 South Africa: Give a Hand and Hope AIDS Project (Box 78, Folder 14)
        - #3732 Tanzania: Mufindi District Women's Forum (Box 78, Folder 15)
        - #3749 Ethiopia: African Services Committee (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - 2009
        - #3781 Uganda: Kikumu Agricultural Research Centre (Box 79, Folder 1)
        - #3783 Kenya: Wahanda Women Development Group (Box 79, Folder 2)
        - #3795 Malawi: Chilimba Women and Orphans Care Group (Box 79, Folder 3)
        - #3805 Georgia: Women's Center (Box 79, Folder 4-11)
        - #3805 Georgia: Women's Center (Box 80, Folder 1)
        - #3820 Kenya: Rise and Shine Women's Group (Box 80, Folder 2)
        - #3826 Sierra Leone: Life for Relief and Development (Box 80, Folder 3)
        - #3831 Cameroon: Bongeh Women Common Initiative Group (Box 80, Folder 4)
        - #3854 Ghana: Akpafu Traditional Birth Attendants Women Association (ATBAWA) (Box 80, Folder 5)
        - #3855 Nigeria: Kids Hope School (Box 80, Folder 6)
        - #3862 Sierra Leone: Women's Participation in Grassroots Development (Box 80, Folder 7)
        - #3880 Uganda: Bibbo Women's Association Development (Box 80, Folder 8)
        - #3934 Ghana: Leklebi Women's Initiative (Box 80, Folder 9-10)
        - #3953 Pakistan: Tanzeem-e-Nau-Jawana (Box 80, Folder 11-12)
        - #3971 Burundi: Bonne Generation de Burundi (Box 80, Folder 13)
        - #4011 Ghana: Prampram: Obemla Co-Operative and Marketing Society Ltd. (Box 80, Folder 14)
        - #4079 Congo: Vocational Training Center for Youth in Distress (Box 80, Folder 15)
        - #4133 Brazil: Bahia Street (Box 80, Folder 16)
        - #4207 Mali: Medicine for Mali, Inc. (Box 80, Folder 17)
        - #4210 China: Yunnan Institute of Development (Box 80, Folder 18)
        - #4259 India: Gene Campaign (Box 80, Folder 19)
- SERIES III. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS AND COMPUTER MEDIA
  - Administration
    - CD-2: VGIF November 2002 Board Meeting, Our New Facilities, 700MB (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Membership, CD-R, 700MB, 2002 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - VGIF Recruitment Poster, CD-R, 700MB, 2004 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Interview with retiring president Virginia Maynard conducted by Claire Fulcher, audio cassette, 120 minutes, Jul 1994 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Committees
    - Project Grants
      - Project 5-0 poster and Powerpoint. CD-R 700MB. 2 disks (Box 81, Folder 5)
        [see also box 19, folder 8 and box 42, folder 7]
      - Photo CD-5: Evelyn Mafeni - Project 1661 - 80 minutes 700MB, Apr 2003 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - CD-5: Projects 1487, 1512, 1563, 1600, 1607, 1654 (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - CD-6: Projects 1692, 1701, 1708, 1727, 1733 (unreadable) (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - 2055 Rwanda: Doctors on Call: Bethsaida Home for Street Children. CD-R 700 MB, 2005 (Box 81, Folder 9)
      - #2192 Pilot project. Tibet: Chungba Video, Engine Pictures. CD-R, 700MB. 2005. (Box 81, Folder 10)
      - #2192 Pilot project. Tibet: Chungba Slideshow 2005. CD-R (Box 81, Folder 11)
        [see also: #1714 in box 64, folders 13-15 and box 71, folders 1-3]
      - #2195 Bolivia: Video "Capacitación Técnica" DVD-RW. 120 minutes, 2005 (Box 81, Folder 12)
      - #2195 Bolivia: Tomas Katari. CD-R 700MB (Box 81, Folder 13)
      - Special Solicitations #2389 and #2546. CD-R 700MB (Box 81, Folder 14)
      - #2491 India: SEEDS, "Thedal: Suppressed Voice," Seeds Trust, Dindigul. CD-R, 700MB (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - VHS
      - Fernando/Sri Lanka: "Our Legacy for Posterity" NTSC, E-120 (Box 81, Folder 16)
      - UNICEF, "Building a World Fit for Children" NTSC, T-10 (Box 81, Folder 17)
      - 32nd Triennial Congress of the International Alliance of Women, E-60 (Box 81, Folder 18)
- SERIES IV. OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Brochures and pamphlets; travel schedules of president Barbara Carey; news articles about Virginia Gildersleeve from 1941; posters from grants; straw folder titled "VGIFUW, 1968-1978;" Bolivian artwork; newspaper from Sierra Leone 1941, 1968-1978, May 1979 (Box 82)
  - First VGIF poster (designed by Claire Fulcher and Virginia Maynard), n.d.; Project posters, travel schedules, maps from projects.undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 1)